Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records 1853-2002 (bulk, 1929-1995) MS 3009-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series II.C. Chairman of the Board and Chief Executive Officer: Andrew Heiskell Files, 1949-1980; 9.1 Linear feet in 10 record cartons
  - Subseries II.C.2. Administrative Files, 1958-1980; 7.35 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    Heiskell's administrative files span his time as chairman of the board and chief executive officer of Time Inc. Subjects generally cover Time Inc. policies; performance and profitability; strategic plans; and acquisition and sales of assets. Specifics include Heiskell's participation in Time Inc.'s continued lobbying on postal rates, with responses from President Gerald Ford and then Senator Joe Biden; involvement in the congressional committee on international communications; and congratulatory letters on the debut of People, the idea for which is attributed to him. He also received reports regarding interests and activities pursued by Time Inc. such as cable television via Time-Life Broadcast and paper production from subsidiary East Texas Pulp and Paper Company (Eastex). His notes on countries include a recap of his visit to artist Salvador Dali.
    For his memoranda files, some folders state that these are select memoranda copied specifically for the archives.
    Besides folders on subjects, his administrative files include folders with correspondence and documents from other Time Inc. executives including and correspondence from other Time Inc. executives including Executive Vice President Bernhard Auer, Group Vice President and Secretary Charles Bear, vice president and Time Publisher Ralph Davidson, Editor-in-Chief Hedley Donovan, Assistant Treasurer J. Winston Fowlkes, Chairman of the Executive Committee James Linen, Treasurer Richard McKeough, Group Vice President of Video Richard Munro, President of Time-Life Films Bruce Paisner, President James Shepley, Director of Personnel Bob Steed, Director of Circulation Kelso Sutton, Director of Public Affairs Bob Sweeney, Assistant Secretary Curt Messinger, and Vice President of Public Affairs Donald Wilson; and board members including Louis Banks, Gaylord A. Freeman, Jr., Alexander Heard, Arthur Keylor, Sol Linowitz, Arthur Temple, Thomas J. Watson, Jr., and Advisory Director Maurice T. Moore.
    Organized alphabetically based on original order with stray files and materials from binders interfiled.
    - Advertising tax: New York City, 1971 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 25)
    - Affirmative action, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 26)
    - Alternative distribution, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 27)
    - American Enterprise Institute, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 28)
    - Argyle Research Corporation (Bantam Books), 1976 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 29)
    - ATC [American Television and Communications Corporation], 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 30)
    - Auer, Bernhard (Bernie), 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 31)
    - Banks, Louis, 1973-1979 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 32)
    - Bear, Charles, 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 580, Folder 33-34)
    - Bear, Charles, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 1-3)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc., 1977 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 4)
    - Cable Television Strategy, 1971 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 5)
    - Cable: Exhibit II: Manhattan Cable Data, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 6)
    - Cable: Exhibit III: CATV background reading, circa 1970 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 7)
    - Color Television, C.A. (Colteve) / Proventel, 1969 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 8)
    - Company practices: Executive retirement, 1974 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 9)
    - The Conference Board, 1971-1980 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 10-12)
    - Cost Control Committee, 1975 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 13)
    - Cravath, Swaine & Moore: Litigation, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 14)
    - Crutcher, Larry, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 15)
    - Davidson, Ralph, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 16)
    - Denman, Joe C., Jr., 1978 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 17)
    - Dignman, Michael, 1977 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 18)
    - Discover, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 19)
    - Donovan, Hedley, 1967-1980 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 20)
    - Dun's review article Aug. 1973 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 21)
    - Eastex, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 582, Folder 22-25)
    - Eastex, 1971 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 1)
    - Eastex: Big Thicket, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 2)
    - Senator Ervin Sub-Committee on Constitutional Rights, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 3)
    - Federal Trade Commission (FTC), 1971 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 4)
    - Ford Foundation: Business and Media Seminar, 1977 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 5)
    - Fortune: General, 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 6)
    - Fortune: Study: Top Advertisers and Agency People Rate Magazines as Vehicles for Advertising, 1974 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 7)
    - Fowlkes, Winston, 1976 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 8)
    - Freeman, Gaylord, 1962-1980 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 9)
    - Gardner, John W., 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 10)
    - General Learning Corp., 1965-1970 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 11)
    - Georgia Kraft, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 12)
    - Goodrich, Henry C., 1980 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 13)
    - Graves, Ralph, 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 14)
    - Grum, Clifford, 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 15)
    - Grunwald, Henry A., 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 16)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1968-1979 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 17)
    - Heiskell: Articles by and about, 1958-1986 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 18-19)
    - Heiskell: Notes on countries around the world, 1960-1961 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 20)
    - Heiskell: Memoranda, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 583, Folder 21-23)
      The memos from 1960 include approximately 35 green vinyl audio discs; 4 in. The discs were mailed from France to Beatrice Casey and probably contain dictation.
    - Heiskell: Memoranda, 1960-1974 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 1-15)
      The 1960 memoranda folder contains a large number of vinyl dictation discs mailed to Beatrice Casey from Heiskell in France.
    - Heiskell: "Thoughts", 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 16)
    - Hoffman, Paul G.: Memorial Fund, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 17)
    - Hood, Alex, 1976-1979 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 18)
    - Horner, Matina, S., 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 19)
    - Hughes-Mc Graw Hill, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 20)
    - Incentive Compensation Plan: 1962, 1961 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 21)
    - Inland Container Corp: Directors meeting, 1979 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 22-23)
    - Inland Container Corp, 1977-1980 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 24-25)
    - Inter American Press Association, 1972-1978 (Offsite-box 584, Folder 26-30)
    - Inter American Press Association, 1958-1971 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 1-6)
    - Japan Visit, 1961 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 7-8)
    - Jones, Charlotte Schiff, 1976 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 9)
    - Keller, Robert T., 1974-1978 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 10)
    - Keppel, Frank, 1974-1977 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 11)
    - Keylor, Arthur W., 1971-1979 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 12)
    - Kundhardt, Phil, 1976 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 13)
    - Laffont, Robert, 1977 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 14)
    - Laybourne, Lawrence E., 1971-1974 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 15)
    - Legal department, 1973-1979 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 16)
    - Life, 1978 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 17)
    - Linen, James A., 1975-1979 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 18)
    - Linowitz, Sol M., 1960-1980 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 19)
    - Little, Brown & Co., 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 20)
    - Luce Fellowships and Memorial, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 21-22)
    - Magazine Development Group, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 23)
    - Manley, Joan D., 1977 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 24)
    - Manhattan Cable TV, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 25-26)
    - Maria Moors Cabot Award, 1979 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 27)
    - Maryland Cup Corporation, 1978-1979 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 1-2)
    - McKeough, Richard B., 1971-1980 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 3)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1977 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 4)
    - Moore, Maurice T., 1976 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 5)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 6)
    - Munro, Dick, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 7)
    - The 1975 Outlook, 1974 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 8)
    - Ostheimer, Richard, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 9)
    - Paisner, Bruce, 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 10)
    - People, 1973-1978 (Offsite-box 585, Folder 11-12)
    - Peterson, Rudolph A., 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 13)
    - Postal Service and Rates, 1970-1978 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 14-21)
    - Presidential letter: Postal service, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 22)
    - Reader's Digest, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 23)
    - Retirement income task force, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 24)
    - Senate subcommittee testimony: June 9, 1977 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 25)
    - Shepley, James R., 1975 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 26)
    - Sports Illustrated, 1972-1977 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 27)
    - Sports Illustrated: United Kingdom Feasibility Study, 1973? (Offsite-box 586, Folder 28)
    - Steed, Bob, 1971-1979 (Offsite-box 586, Folder 29-30)
    - Steed, Bob, 1971-1979 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 1)
    - Student vote, 1971 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 2)
    - Study: Newspaper publishing, 1972 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 3-4)
    - Subscription Services Division, 1979 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 5-6)
    - Sutton, Kelso, 1972 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 7)
    - Sweeney, Bob, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 8)
    - Synanon, 1978 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 9)
    - Tax problems: International, 1961-1969 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 10)
    - Temple, Arthur, 1973-1978 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 11-12)
    - Temple Industries, 1973, 1983 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 13-14)
    - Temple-Eastex: General, 1973-1978 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 15-18)
    - Temple-Eastex: Board Meetings, 1978 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 19-20)
    - Temple-Eastex: Compensation committee meeting, 1978 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 21)
    - Temple-Eastex: Operations, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 22)
    - Time: 50th anniversary, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 23)
    - Time: Fox Hill Meeting (strategic planning), 1967 (Offsite-box 587, Folder 24)
    - Time: Heiskell as acting publisher, 1977 January 17-February 7 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 1)
    - Time - Hughes project, 1973 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 2-3)
    - Time Inc.: General, 1960 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 4)
    - Time Inc.: Broadcasting, 1961-1974 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 5-8)
    - Time Inc.: Management Compensation Study, 1970 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 9)
    - Time Inc.: Messinger, Curt, 1968 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 10)
    - Time-Life Books, 1971-1976 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 11)
    - Time-Life Broadcast: General, 1960-1970 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 12-13)
    - Time-Life Broadcast: WOTV, 1978 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 14)
    - Time-Life Films, 1970-1979 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 15)
    - Unishield, 1972 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 16)
    - United Way of Tri-State, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 17)
    - Valk, Garry: Life, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 18)
    - Wainwright, Loudon: Life History, 1976 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 19)
    - Walker, Charls: Charls Walker Associates, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 20)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 21)
    - Warner, Rawleigh, Jr.: Mobil Oil Corporation, 1970-1978 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 22)
    - Watson, Thomas J., Jr., 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 23)
    - Welch, Paul, 1971 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 24)
    - Werner, Lucy, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 25)
    - Wilson, Donald M., 1971-1979 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 26)
    - Windrose-DuMont-Time, 1969 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 27)
    - Woman magazine, 1976-1977 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 28)
    - Women at Time Inc., 1973 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 29)
    - Wootton, Phil: Research and Development, 1965-1967 (Offsite-box 588, Folder 30)
  - Subseries II.C.3. Speech Files, 1949-1980; 0.84 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Speech Files contain transcripts and other material related to speeches made by Heiskell primarily as the chairman of the board and chief executive officer of Time Inc. The General Speeches folder includes some speeches prior to his appointment as chairman. It also contains a transcript of his support for a bill to enact the Fair Housing Act of 1967 ("Title IV of the civil rights bill S-1358"). His speeches include testimony to Congressional committees, key notes at university commencements and advertisers conventions, and speeches on the topics of economic issues such as urban housing and cost of living and freedom of the press. As Heiskell is cited as a founder of the National Urban Coalition and co-chair from 1967 to 1979, many of his speeches may have been in this role.
    "The 1993 Frankel Awards." Humanities, National Endowment for the Humanities, November/December 1993.
    Organized chronologically based on original order.
    - List of Speeches 1940-1980 (Offsite-box 581, Folder 1-2)
    - General Speeches, 1949-1967 (Offsite-box 581, Folder 3)
    - 1968 January 17: Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (Offsite-box 581, Folder 4)
    - 1968 March 15: Senate Banking and Currency Committee on Proposed Housing Legislation: (Offsite-box 581, Folder 5)
    - 1968 April 17: United Negro College Fund: Detroit, Michigan (Offsite-box 581, Folder 6)
    - 1968 April 24: National Conference of Christians and Jews: Kansas City, Missouri (Offsite-box 581, Folder 7)
    - 1968 May 14: Founders Day Dinner of Indiana Chapter of Sigma Delta Chi (Offsite-box 581, Folder 8)
    - 1968 May 14: WFBM and Indianapolis Chamber of Commerce (Offsite-box 581, Folder 9)
    - 1968 May 23: Investment Analysts Society of Chicago (Offsite-box 581, Folder 10)
    - 1968 May 23: Cornerstone Ceremony for the Time & Life Building: Chicago, Illinois (Offsite-box 581, Folder 11)
    - 1968 June 9: Shaw University (Offsite-box 581, Folder 12)
      Includes audiovisual material.
      1 audiotape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, stereo; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Tape of Heiskell speech Shaw U. - June '68."
    - 1968 October: "Coalition for Crisis" MBA Magazine Interview (Offsite-box 581, Folder 13)
    - 1968 October 2: American Bankers Association: Chicago, Illinois (Offsite-box 581, Folder 14)
    - 1968 October 17: Inter American Press Association: Buenos Aires, Argentina (Offsite-box 581, Folder 15)
    - 1968 October 28: Brotherhood Award of Brotherhood in Action (Offsite-box 581, Folder 16)
    - 1968 November 11: U.S. Savings & Loan League: Miami, Florida (Offsite-box 581, Folder 17)
    - 1968 December 4: Wharton Alumni: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Offsite-box 581, Folder 18)
    - 1968 December 9: Urban Coalition: Denver, Colorado (Offsite-box 581, Folder 19)
    - 1969 January 9: National Retail Merchants Association (Offsite-box 581, Folder 20)
    - 1969 March 13: Remarks at Stillman Dinner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 21)
    - 1969 May 26: International Magazine Conference: Williamsburg, Virginia (Offsite-box 581, Folder 22)
    - 1969 June 8: Lake Erie Commencement (Offsite-box 581, Folder 23)
    - 1969 June 10: Edison Electrical Institute: Portland, Oregon (Offsite-box 581, Folder 24)
    - 1969 June 21: Second Circuit Judiciary Conference: Manchester, Vermont (Offsite-box 581, Folder 25)
    - 1969 October 8: Cities in a Race with Time: New York City YMCA (Offsite-box 581, Folder 26)
    - 1969 November 18: Regional Plan Association (Offsite-box 581, Folder 27)
    - 1969 November 25: 6th Annual Corporate Pension Conference (Offsite-box 581, Folder 28)
    - 1971 October: Alleghany County United Fund (Offsite-box 581, Folder 29)
    - 1971 October 20: Importance of Advertising to America's Free Press (Offsite-box 581, Folder 30)
    - 1971 October 20: Joint ANA [Association of National Advertisers]-AAAA [American Association of Advertising Agencies] Committee: Federal Trade Commission (Offsite-box 581, Folder 31)
    - 1971 December 7: World Affairs Council: Los Angeles, California (Offsite-box 581, Folder 32)
    - 1971 February 4: Detroit Adcraft, 1972 (Offsite-box 581, Folder 33)
    - 1972 February 6: Hofstra Commencement (Offsite-box 581, Folder 34)
    - 1972 February 8: Statement before Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights: Senate Committee on the Judiciary (Offsite-box 581, Folder 35)
    - 1972 May 3: State of National Urban Coalition: House Committee on Ways and Means (Offsite-box 581, Folder 36)
    - 1972 June 7: City Club, New York, New York (Offsite-box 581, Folder 37)
    - 1972 June 22: Statement before Subcommittee on Postal Service (Offsite-box 581, Folder 38)
    - 1972 October 18: Roy E. Larsen Reception (Offsite-box 581, Folder 39)
    - 1973 June 13: FIPP World Magazine Congress, Stockholm, Sweden (Offsite-box 581, Folder 40)
    - 1973 November 14: Cost of Living Council (Offsite-box 581, Folder 41)
    - 1974 March 19: Regional Plan Association (Offsite-box 581, Folder 42)
    - 1974 April 25: Acida Lunch (Offsite-box 581, Folder 43)
    - 1974 May 16: American Jewish Committee Mass Media Award to Katharine Graham (Offsite-box 581, Folder 44)
    - 1974 September 11: Time Advertising Sales Convention: Puerto Rico (Offsite-box 581, Folder 45)
    - 1974 September 30: Time-Life Films Meeting: Bermuda (Offsite-box 581, Folder 46)
    - 1974 October 3: B'nai B'rith Award to John Gardner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 47)
    - 1974 October 17: United Negro College Fund 30th Anniversary Dinner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 48)
    - 1974 October 24: Time Inc. Staff Meeting (Offsite-box 581, Folder 49)
    - 1974 November: On Our Minds: Radio Conversations with Ambassador Sol Linowitz (Offsite-box 581, Folder 50)
    - 1974 November 14: Stock Option Group (Offsite-box 581, Folder 51)
    - 1975 April 17: Time Inc. Staff Meeting (Offsite-box 581, Folder 52)
    - 1975 April 24: Investment Capital Conference: Lyford Cay (Offsite-box 581, Folder 53)
    - 1975 April 29: Institute on Man and Science Award: New York, New York (Offsite-box 581, Folder 54)
    - 1975 May 28: Houston Security Analysts (Offsite-box 581, Folder 55)
    - 1975 May 29: New York Security Analysts: Furman Selz Mager Dietz and Birney Inc. (Offsite-box 581, Folder 56)
    - 1975 November 5: French Television Interview (Offsite-box 581, Folder 57)
    - 1975 November 11: Citizens Union Dinner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 58)
    - 1975 November 25: Los Angeles Society of Financial Analysts (Offsite-box 581, Folder 59)
    - 1976 March 12: Statement for Bicentennial Issue of Ad Age (Offsite-box 581, Folder 60)
    - 1976 April 6: National Cable Television Association: Dallas, Texas (Offsite-box 581, Folder 61)
    - 1976 May 20: Time Inc. Staff Meeting (Offsite-box 581, Folder 62)
    - 1976 August 12: Public Relations World Congress: Boston, Massachusetts (Offsite-box 581, Folder 63)
    - 1976 November 18: Time Inc. Staff Meeting (Offsite-box 581, Folder 64)
    - 1977 January 24: National Association of Home Builders: Nathaniel Rogg Retirement (Offsite-box 581, Folder 65)
    - 1977 February 2: Regional Planning Association honoring Kim Norton (Offsite-box 581, Folder 66)
    - 1977 February 14: Time Inc. Listing on London Exchange (Offsite-box 581, Folder 67)
    - 1977 March 20: Fortune Corporate Communications Seminar: Port St. Lucie, Florida (Offsite-box 581, Folder 68)
    - 1977 March 21: Temple-Eastex Dinner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 69)
    - 1977 May 10: International Advertising Association (Offsite-box 581, Folder 70)
    - 1977 May 12: Roy Larsen 55th Anniversary Dinner and Dance (Offsite-box 581, Folder 71)
    - 1977 May 18: Time Inc Dinner: Detroit, Michigan (Offsite-box 581, Folder 72)
    - 1977 June 9: Senate International Operations: International Frequency Allocations (Offsite-box 581, Folder 73)
    - 1978 February 2: "Building for America's Future": New York National Business Leadership Conference (Offsite-box 581, Folder 74)
    - 1978 March 15: R. R. Donnelly 50th Anniversary Dinner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 75)
    - 1978 April 25: "The Mood in America": IAA Meeting (Offsite-box 581, Folder 76)
    - 1978 June 28: Time Inc. Lease Signing Ceremony (Offsite-box 581, Folder 77)
    - 1978 August 24: Presentation of Distinguished Service Awards: New York Urban Coalition (Offsite-box 581, Folder 78)
    - 1978 September 13: Time Inc. Conference on Taxation (Offsite-box 581, Folder 79)
    - 1978 October 18: International Communications in an Information Society (Offsite-box 581, Folder 80)
    - 1979 March 6: 4th Annual Catalyst Awards (Offsite-box 581, Folder 81)
    - 1979 June 20: Paine Webber (Offsite-box 581, Folder 82)
    - 1979 October 17: ICD Dinner: Presentation of award to Rawleigh Warner (Offsite-box 581, Folder 83)
    - 1980 March 10: "Communications: Some Full-Grown Progeny of a Recent Marriage": Detroit Economic Club (Offsite-box 581, Folder 84)
    - 1980 March 13: Gaylord Freeman Retirement Party (Offsite-box 581, Folder 85)
    - 1980 May 5: March of Dimes Partner in Science Award (Offsite-box 581, Folder 86)
- Series II.D. Office of the President and Chairman of the Board: Ralph P. Davidson Files, 1978-1987; 3.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  Ralph P. Davidson joined Time Inc. in 1954 as an advertising salesman for Life. In 1969 Time promoted him to an associate publisher position and by 1972 he was the publisher. With this promotion, Time Inc. also made Davidson a vice president of the company. From late 1978 through 1980, he served in a special assistant position to Time Inc. President James Shepley. The Time Inc. board of directors elected Davidson to join in April 1980 and in June elected him to the position of chairman. He served in this role through at least 1985. By 1987 he was chairman of the executive committee. Davidson left Time Inc. in 1988 to take a role as chairman of the Kennedy Center in Washington.
  Langer, Emily. "Ralph P. Davidson, former chairman of Time Inc. and Kennedy Center, dies at 86." The Washington Post, August 2, 2014. https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/obituaries/ralph-p-davidson-former-chairman-of-time-inc-and-kennedy-center-dies-at-86/2014/08/02/905dfed4-166f-11e4-9e3b-7f2f110c6265_story.html.
  Ralph P. Davidson's files include his files from roles as chairman of the board, outside charitable work while chairman, and as assistant to Time Inc. President James Shepley.
  Subseries II.D.1. Chairman of the Board: Subject Files
  Subseries II.D.2. Chairman of the Board: American Corporate Aid for Lebanon Inc. Files
  Subseries II.D.3. Office of the President: Assistant Files
  - Subseries II.D.1. Chairman of the Board: Subject Files, 1978-1987; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    Ralph Davidson's subject files document his work regarding following legislation or government committees regarding issues that could affect Time Inc. and corresponding with congresspeople and others on these matters. The files were sent to the archives by Davidson's assistant Elza Forster.
    - Archives transfer note, 1987 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 1)
    - Cable Legislation, 1983-1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 2-3)
    - Employee Equal Opportunity Roundtables, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 4)
    - Gannett Company: Life: Trademark, 1983 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Cable, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 6)
    - Minority Business Development Program, 1985 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 7)
    - Pornography Commission, 1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 8-9)
    - Postal Affairs, 1978-1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 10-12)
    - Tender Offer Legislation, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 13)
    - Time Canada: General, 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 4207, Folder 14-15)